Finding aid for the Paul Monette papers, 1945-1995 LSC.1707
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 4: Writings
  - Subseries 4.4: Nonfiction/Memoirs
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Letters of congratulation from friends, fellow writers, those who knew Roger or Cesar, etc. Fan mail filed elsewhere., n.d. / v.d. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Diane Rehm show [interview?]., July 7, 1988.; 1 audio cassette. (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Paperback sale(?) Letter from Michael Kazan (Avon Books)., June 3, 1988.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Party invitation., June 25, 1988.; Printed (?) card. 2 copies. (Box 19, Folder 5)
      David Bohnett and Rand Schrader invite you to celebrate the publication of Borrowed Time: An AIDS Memoir ....
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Interview, Good Day, WCVB (Boston)., July 6, 1988.; 1 video cassette. (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Awards. National Book Critics Circle nomination., 1988.; 1 leaf [calligraphed?]. Signed by Nina King. (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Also postcard (The Threepenny Review) from Wendy Lesser. n.d. (January 10). Typed, signed.
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Reading at LATC. Review and program., January 1, 1989. (Box 19, Folder 7)
      In: Los Angeles Herald Examiner. Event was in November 1988.
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Lecture / Reading. University of California Santa Barbara., January 13, 1989. (Box 19, Folder 8)
      Letter of invitation with notes.
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Lecture / reading. University of California, Santa Barbara. Press release., January 17, 1989. (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Clippings University of California, Santa Barbara., February 6-8, 1989. (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: The 1st Annual Lambda Literary Awards Banquet (program)., June 2, 1989. (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Borrowed Time and Love Alone nominated.
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Invitation to Bay Area Physicians for Human Rights annual banquet. PM was guest speaker., December 8, 1989. (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Reviews for Borrowed Time and Love Alone., n.d. / v.d. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: French translation. Correspondence from Manuela Dumay., 1988-1989.; 2 cards. Holograph. 1 typescript letter. (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Award for French translation. Grand Prix Litteraire du Medec 1990. Letter from Fabienne Delmote. Enclosures with names of jury, etc., 1 item, 6 pieces. (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Letters received from Bill Bowersock about setting BT to music. Includes score of We have been here., October 10, 1993 and April 11, 1994. (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Sound recording of Bill Bowersock We have been here., 1994.; 1 cassette tape. (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Tony Goldwyn reading from Borrowed Time, Arts & Entertainment Revue., November 28, 1990.; 1 video cassette. (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Correspondence regarding Books-on-Tape version., 1994. (Box 19, Folder 17)
      From The American Audio Prose Company. Tape of PM reading Borrowed Time.
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 28, Folder 4-5)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., 1988-1994 (inclusive). (Box 25, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from: Alfred Corn (?), Katherine V. Forrest, David Groff, Joseph Hardy, Andrew Holleran, Rudy Kikel, William Koelsch.
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., n.d. / v.d. (Box 25, Folder 5)
      Includes letters from: Craig Lucas, John Mazzitello, S.J., James Merrill, Carol Muske.
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., n.d. / v.d. (Box 25, Folder 6)
      Includes letters from: Eric Rofes, Vito Russo, John Schlesinger, David Schorr.
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Fan Mail: Friends of Roger., n.d. / v.d. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Fan Mail: Friends of friends., n.d. / v.d. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Fan Mail: Andover (town)., n.d. / v.d. (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Borrowed Time: an Aids Memoir: Fan Mail: Yale and Phillips Academy., n.d. / v.d. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - The Meek Are Contesting the Will: In: Frontiers. vol.9 issue 15., November 23, 1990.; pp.23-24, 26-27. (Box 40, Folder 2)
      The following address was delivered by Paul Monette at the UCLA Gay and Lesbian Writers Conference.
      See Box 4 (folder 2)
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story [c. 1992]: In: The Advocate [two parts]. (?)., March 1991 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      First part has introduction by Mark Thompson. Called autobiography in progress.
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story [c. 1992]: Letter received re Advocate excerpt(s). Encloses poem., March 26, 1991. (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story [c. 1992]: Letter from Denise Accardi., May 28, 1991.; Notecard. Typed, signed. (Box 22, Folder 16)
      re excerpt(s) in Advocate.
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story [c. 1992]: Excerpts in: QW, Out of New York. no.29., May 17, 1992. (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story [c. 1992]: Excerpts in: Yale GALA., September 1992. (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story [c. 1992]: Publicity tour items. (?)., June 1992 (Box 22, Folder 19)
      Includes letter from staff, Sonya Live. June 30, 1992.
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story [c. 1992]: Interviews. In: The Advocate () with excerpt, interview with Owen Keehnen. (clipping)., 1992. June 2, 1992 September 1992 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story [c. 1992]: Reviews and mentions., 1992 primarily. (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story [c. 1992]: Letters from people mentioned in the book., 1992-1994. (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story [c. 1992]: Letters of appreciation from friends., n.d. / v.d. (Box 22, Folder 23)
      See also: Get Well card from Lambda Rising Book Store (Washington, D.C.).
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Card from Lambda Rising., n.d. / v.d. (Box 36, Folder 10)
      Get well card from store employees.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Letters of appreciation which mention Andover, etc., n.d. / v.d. (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Ed Anderson's Journal. Guest: Paul Monette., May 11, 1992.; 1 video cassette (VHS). (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Note from Ed Anderson., June 21, 1992.; 1 leaf. Holograph, signed. Enclosing videotape. (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Press kit., August 10, 1992. (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Made for offering paperback rights for bidding.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Letters from Kevin Bentley and Matthew Lore., v.d. (Box 23, Folder 2)
      About paperback sales, backlist, etc. Harper San Francisco. August 20, September 11, 1992; July 16, August 13, September 3, 1993; September 19, 1994. ML letter is September 11, 1992. 1994 letter mentions Gay Soul and Sister and Brother anthologies.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Honors. National Book Awards nomination certificate., 1992.; 1 [printed?] leaf [removed from frame]. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      1992 nonfiction finalist.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Letters Received: After National Book Award nomination, announcement, etc., October 1992-June 1993. (Box 23, Folder 4)
      From: Sascha Bittner, Gay Block, Peter Bunnell, Alexander (Cobbold?), Malka Drucker, Spence Halperin, Barbara Horwitz, Tim Miller, Doug Sadownick.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Honors. National Book Award ceremonies program., November 18, 1992. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Honors. The Politics of Silence. Library of Congress Center for the Book lecture., n.d.; [12] leaves. Typescript (photocopy) with holograph corrections, holograph. (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Part of the text is in outline form with extensive holograph corrections and one leaf holograph. With this: copy of State Univeristy of New York Oswego address (refiled).
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Honors. Library of Congress Center for The Book Lecture by Paul Monette [transcription]. Date of lecture., January 28, 1993.; 52 leaves. Typescript (photocopy). (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Honors., February 22 and April 1993. (Box 23, Folder 8)
      Article and clippings about Library of Congress speech.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Honors. National Book Award articles and mentions., 1992-1993.; Clippings, primarily. (Box 23, Folder 9)
      Some refer to the controversy of award winner Dorothy Allison's ban from speaking in Oklahoma.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Honors. National Book Award. Letter from Robert Roehr., February 17, 1993.; 1 leaf. Typed, not signed. (Box 23, Folder 10)
      From editor of 10 Percent Magazine requesting permission to reprint portions of PM's acceptance speece.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Honors. The Politics of Silence [excerpts from Library of Congress lecture]. In: The New York Times OP-ED., 1993 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Honors. The Politics of Silence [excerpts from Library of Congress lecture]. In: 10 Percent., Summer 1993.; p.8. (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Honors. Also snapshot., February 23, 1993. (Box 23, Folder 12)
      Letter from Susan Hoffman, chair, Gay / Lesbian Book Award, American Library Association.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Letter from Christopher Sands to Lambda Book Report., March 3, 1993.; Photocopy. (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Letter from John Preston about Lambda Book Report review. (?)., 1993; Holograph on notecard, signed Prest. (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Letter from Donald Corren about movie rights., March 15, 1993.; Typed, signed. 1 item, 2 pieces. (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Remainder statement., May 1993. (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Letter from Barry Herem enclosing review., August 17, 1993. (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Exhibits. Letter from Dan Luckenbill (), enclosing UCLA Librarian article. vol.46 no.1 ()., October 22, 1993 Spring / Summer 1993; 1 typed leaf, signed. (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Letters received from David Rosen, Quality Paperback., 1993-1994.; 2 letters and catalogs. (Box 23, Folder 19)
      Mentions Time Warner forum and Last Watch of the Night.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Letters from Andrew Wille, Little Brown (England)., June 3 and December 9, 1993; February 4 and August 15, 1994.; All letters are typed, signed. (Box 23, Folder 20)
      Details of Abacus reprint, wrapper photograph (Bruce Weber), reviews, etc.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Reprint: English edition reviews., 1994.; Photocopies. (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Reprint/Translation: Letter received requesting an Author's foreword for Japanese translation of Becoming a Man. Includes snapshot of PM with author., June 8, 1994. (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Letter from Steve Murray about stage adaption., n.d.; Typed, signed (photocopy). Holograph notes on copy by Wendy Weil. (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., 1991-1993 (inclusive), n.d. (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Includes letters from: Bill Clinton (Fax), Kate Clinton, Alison Bechdel, Betty Berzon, Robert Dawidoff, Nisa Donnelly, Katherine V. Forrest.
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., 1992-1994 (inclusive). (Box 25, Folder 9)
      Includes letters from: Eric Garber, Ellen Gavin, Boze Hadleigh, Rudy Kikel, Terrence McNally.
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., 1992-1994 (inclusive), n.d. (Box 25, Folder 10)
      Includes letters from: Tim Miller, James Carroll Pickett, Robert Patrick, John Preston (FAX), Doug Sadownick, Linda Gray Sexton, Barbara Smith.
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
      Letter from Stephen Rotondaro added (to Box 31, folder 3).
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 32, Folder 1-3)
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story: Fan Mail: Phillips Academy., n.d. / v.d. (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Becoming A Man: Half a Life Story: Fan Mail: From German student., September 29, 1993.; Oversize greeting card. Hand made. (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Becoming a Man: Half a Life Story: Fan Mail, Mike Walsh, 1993 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Borrowed Time and Becoming A Man: Post-Publication Material / Adaption: Requests from Christopher Tibbetts to make PM's works into a play., July 11 and August 20, 1994. (Box 47, Folder 24)
    - "The Politics of Silence," Od-Ed: The New York Times, 1993 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Mantrack / Guest Opinion [Playboy Magazine]: Uncorrected proof., February 9, 1993.; 1 folded leaf. (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Mantrack / Guest Opinion [Playboy Magazine]: In: Playboy. vol.40 no.5., May 1993.; p.40. (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Mantrack / Guest Opinion [Playboy Magazine]: Letter from Dorothy B. Atcheson., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 39)
      Accompanied copies of issue containing essay.
    - Beauty and the Noble Beast: Letter to editor. In: Frontiers., July 2, 1993.; Clipping. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Last Watch of the Night: My Priests: Letters from priests: from John A. Mazzitello and Otis Charles. 24 March from OC, others JM., March 24, 30 and April 4, 1993. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Last Watch of the Night: My Priests: Letter from Rachel A. Peller, The New Yorker., June 11, 1993.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Written as Tina Brown's assistant, rejecting Gert and Visiting the Dead.
    - Last Watch of the Night: My Priests: PM or WW: Long hand notes on essays while traveling (3 sets) 1993., July 30, etc.-October 5, 1993.; 24 leaves. total. Holograph on lined paper from notepads. (Box 24, Folder 4)
      Beginning: Roger and I wandered around, ... They developed a rigorous skepticism, ... I'll sleep when I'm dead, .... With other notes.
    - Last Watch of the Night: My Priests: Draft., December 10-18, 1993.; 12 leaves. Holograph. On sheets from lined tablet. (Box 24, Folder 5)
      PM's note: Part of Mortal Things, pp.21-50 written in Polynesia.
    - Last Watch of the Night: Special edition. vol.1 of 2., December 1993.; 2 volumes. (Box 24, Folder 6)
      PM note: A limited edition of these essays has been prepared for the author's friends. 25 in all. This is copy #8.
    - Last Watch of the Night: Special edition. vol.2 of 2., December 1993. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Last Watch of the Night: Publisher's catalog(?)., n.d. (Box 24, Folder 8)
      Leaf torn from catalog, Harvest Books.
    - Last Watch of the Night: Dustjacket art board., n.d. (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Last Watch of the Night: PM's publicity notes., n.d.; 3 leaves. Holograph on Fax form and blank paper. (Box 24, Folder 9)
      Sent from Four Seasons Hotel Boston To Drenka Willien, Harcourt Brace.
    - Last Watch of the Night: 3275: In: Frontiers. vol.12 issue 27., May 6, 1994.; pp.50-60. (Box 40, Folder 4)
      Reprinted in Last Watch of the Night as 3275.
    - Last Watch of the Night: Publicity tour itinerary. (?). Includes date for ABA appearance., May 1994 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Last Watch of the Night: Press kit prepared for ABA, letter. (?). Letter from Chris regarding publicity, copies of previous reviews, print of Gay Block's photograph, etc., May 1994 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Last Watch of the Night: Invitation to publisher's party. RSVP: Dori Weintraub, held Maple Drive, Beverly Hills., May 29, 1994. (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Last Watch of the Night: Letter., March 8, 1994 and n.d. (Box 24, Folder 13)
      Enclosing review, interview transcript. From Steven Bach, Bob Roehr (interview).
    - Last Watch of the Night: Reviews., n.d. / v.d.; Clippings and photocopies. (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Last Watch of the Night: Letters from friends (video)., 1 video cassette (VHS). (Box 39, Folder 3)
      From Andover friend Cinnie Thompson.
    - Last Watch of the Night: Letter from Judy Wieder, enclosing issues of The Advocate with reviews., January 6, 1995.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 36, Folder 1)
      Two issues of The Advocate in publicity folder. Filed in Box 36 (folder 17) (OVERSIZE)
    - Last Watch of the Night: Letter from Andrew Wille about English edition., January 31, 1995.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed Andrew Wille. (Box 24, Folder 15)
      Encloses proof of wrapper, has Post-It correction to text made by PM.
    - Last Watch of the Night: Honors. Mention, Nomination for Lambda Literary Award. Also nominated: West of Yesterday East of Summer., 1995. (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Last Watch of the Night: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., 1990-1994 (inclusive). (Box 25, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from: Kathleen A. Bursley, Dennis DeBiese, John D'Emilio, Michael Denneny, Christine Downing, Malka Drucker, Marcia Finks.
    - Last Watch of the Night: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., n.d. / v.d. (Box 25, Folder 12)
      Includes letters from: Richard Isay, Rudy Kikel, William A. Koelsch (A. Nolder Gay), Merloyd Lawrence, Sister Marti (Starcross).
    - Last Watch of the Night: Letters of Appreciation: From writers / friends., n.d. / v.d. (Box 25, Folder 13)
      Includes letters from: Sascha Bittner, J.D. McClatchy, Alan Mandell, Bill O'Sullivan, Paul Reed, David Roman, Linda Gray Sexton, Patricia Nell Warren.
    - Last Watch Of The Night: Puck: Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
    - Last Watch of the Night: Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 33, Folder 4-6)
    - Last Watch of the Night: [Excerpt] In: Frontiers vol.12 issue 27., May 6-20, 1994.; pp.50-51, 53-54, 57, 59-60. (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - "Last Watch of the Night": Correspondences, Harcourt and Winston Wilde, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - "Last Watch of the Night": Manuscript, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - "Last Watch of the Night": Manuscript, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - "Last Watch of the Night": Galley, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - "Last Watch of the Night": Galley, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - "Last Watch of the Night": Galley, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - "Last Watch of the Night": Galley, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - "Last Watch of the Night": Galley, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - "Last Watch of the Night": Galley, 1994 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Gay Soul / On Becoming: Transcription of interview with Mark Thompson and MT's introduction. (?)., 1993; [22] leaves. Typescript (word processing?). With Post-It note from MT. (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Gay Soul / On Becoming: Page proofs., n.d.; 13pp. Photocopies. (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Gay Soul / On Becoming: Letters from Mark Thompson. Also greeting card., August 24 and October 2, 1993.; Each is 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Gay Soul / On Becoming: Letter from staff (signature illegible), Harper San Francisco. (?)., March 8, 1994; 2 leaves. Holograph. On postcard and notepaper. (Box 47, Folder 6)
      Refers to wrappers for Gay Soul, etc.
    - Gay Soul / On Becoming: Letters Received: Also refers to One Way Fare., November 15, 1993. (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Sister and Brother: Lesbians and Gay Men Write About One Another / Gert: Letter from Merloyd Lawrence Books., March 23, 1993.; 4 leaves. Typescript, signed Merloyd. 4 leaves. (Box 47, Folder 7)
      Giving reactions to PM's manuscript about Gert Macy, ML's maternal aunt.
    - Sister and Brother: Lesbians and Gay Men Write About One Another / Gert: Letter from John Preston., December 13, 1992.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Sister and Brother: Lesbians and Gay Men Write About One Another / Gert: Letter from Joan Nestle., August 28, 1993.; 1 leaf (from word processor?). Incomplete(?). Numbered 2, does not have leaf with signature or copy of contract. (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Sister and Brother: Lesbians and Gay Men Write About One Another / Gert: Letter from Merloyd Lawrence Books., January 28, 1994.; 1 leaf. Holograph, signed. Two photographs. (Box 47, Folder 10)
      Enclosing photographs of Gert Macy. Photographs identified: Gert Macy, Robert Benchley, late 30s(?), Gert Macy, Martha's Vineyard late 1940s(?).
    - A Difficult Celebration: A Voice from 'the Generation of the Incomplete' Contemplates the Gay Nation 25 Years After the Stonewall Uprising that Launched a Movement: In: Los Angeles Times Magazine., June 19, 1994.; pp.16-18. (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Editorial Response: The Advocate: Letters printed in the Advocate., November 15, 1994. (Box 47, Folder 13)
      re article by Bruce Bawer. From Paul Monette and Winston Wilde. And Teresa DeCrescenzo. Printed in the letters to the editor column.
    - Publicity: Letter from Rudy Kikel., February 3, 1995.; 1 leaf. Holograph, signed verso. (Box 47, Folder 16)
      Thanks PM for doing book blurb: we're together again in the book 'one last time'.
    - Choosing My Religion: Letter from Out magazine staff member., February 10, 1995.; 1 notecard. Holograph, signed verso. Signature illegible. (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Choosing My Religion: In: Out., May 1995.; p.136. (Box 47, Folder 19)
      Excerpt from St. Thomas the Apostle Episcopal Church of Hollywood speech, given November 6, 1994.
    - "Seeing in the Dark": Manuscript and Proposal, 1994-1995 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 4.5: Fan Mail and Miscellaneous
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials, please notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
    - The Serpent's Tooth: Editorship, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 3)
      College publication. PM on editorial board.
    - A Rock and a Hard Place: One Boy's Triumphant Story: Foreword: Letter from Tony Johnson., August 7, 1991.; 1 leaf. Holograph, signed verso. (Box 21, Folder 12)
      A fan letter about Borrowed Time and Love Alone. Unknown if this letter accompanied TJ's manuscript.
    - A Rock and a Hard Place: One Boy's Triumphant Story: Foreword: See Farther, Fly Highest, dedicated to Paul Monette With Love from Anthony R. Johnson 1991 [short memoir]., [1], 10 leaves. Holograph. Title and dedicatory first leaf. (Box 21, Folder 13)
      Published as chapter of A Rock and a Hard Place. Also 5 × 7 color photograph: To my friend Paul, love Tony 13 yrs old.
    - A Rock and a Hard Place: One Boy's Triumphant Story: Foreword: Letter from David Groff, Rudy [Kikel], from Winston Wilde (copy) to Newsweek., June 10, 1993 and n.d.; Primarily photocopies. (Box 21, Folder 14)
      A file of copies of reviews, including that by Michele Ingrassia (Newsweek) implying the book is a ruse, photocopy of WW's letter to her June 10, 1993.